A Guide to the Code of Virginia Recodification records of the Virginia Code Commission, 1904-2009
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1974-1997 [Acc. 37986]., Extent: 34 cu. ft. (34 boxes). (Box 1-34)
  - Title 13.1: Stock Corporation Act, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 13-15, 17-18)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 123-126, 128)
  - Title 28.2: Fisheries and Habitat of the Tidal Waters, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 48-52)
  - Title 60.1: Unemployment Compensation Act and Title 54.1 Professions & Occupations, 1979-1987 (Box 6, Folder 41-43, 47, 308)
  - Title 38.1: Insurance, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 34-39)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 5, 75, 154-158)
  - Title 32.1: Health, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 22-27, 29)
  - Title 51.1: Virginia Retirement System, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 59-63)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 129-132)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1983, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 133-142)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 143-150)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 151-153, 165, 168-169, 178-179, 195-196, 264, 266-267, 270-277)
  - Title 38.2: Insurance, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 30-33)
  - Title 28.2: Fisheries & Habitat of the Tidal Waters, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 53-58)
  - Title 46.2: Motor Vehicles and Title 58.2: Taxation, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 64-69, 299)
  - Title 29.1: Game, Inland Fisheries & Boating; Title 37.1: Mental Health Mental Retardation; Title 47.1: Notary Law,; and Title 51.1: Virginia Retirement System, 1976-1989 (Box 18, Folder 71-73, 77-78)
  - Title 8.1: Civil Remedies & Procedure; Title 18.2: Criminal Laws & Title 19.2: Criminal Procedure; and Title 65.1: Workers' Compensation Act, 1974-1990 (Box 19, Folder 81, 91-95)
  - Title 53.1: Prisons & Corrections, 1981, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 96, 97, 98, 102)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 104-108)
  - Title 58.1: Taxation, 1982-1984 (Box 22, Folder 109-122)
  - Title 15.2: Counties, Cities & Towns, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 159-160, 167-169, 170-174)
  - Title 15.2: Counties, Cities & Towns, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 161-166, 175-192)
  - Title 15.2: Counties, Cities & Towns, 1995-1997 (Box 25, Folder 79, 193-218)
  - Title 15.2: Counties, Cities & Towns, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 220-230)
  - Title 15.2: Elections, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 85, 223, 238-242, 263)
  - Title 4.1: Alcohol Beverage Control; and Title 24.2: Elections, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 86, 243-247, 249-251)
  - Title 4.1: Alcohol Beverage Control, 1992-1993 (Box 29, Folder 252-255)
  - Title 4.1: Alcohol Beverage Control, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 256-261)
  - Title 24.2: Elections, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 231-232, 235-237)
  - Title 10.1: Conservation & Environmental Laws; Title 14.1 and Title 17 Folder A and B; and Title 35.1: Hotels, Restaurants & Camps, 1979-1980, 1987, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 40, 83, 101)
  - Title 38.2: Insurance; and Title 58: Taxation, 1983, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 280, 309)
  - Title 4.1: Alcohol Beverage Control, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 262, 307)
- Series III: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1904 [Acc. 41443]., Extent: 1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes). (Box 1-3)
  This series consists of scrapbooks with chapters of the Virginia code glued in them.
  - To examine the Office of Register of the Land Office [Senate], Offices and Officers of the Capital House, Chapter 20: Superintendent of Public Buildings, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Committee No. 2, Chapters 1, 2, 131, 132, 149, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Counties, Cities, and Towns [Senate], Chapters 44-45: Cities and Towns, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General laws [Senate], Militia and Police House, Title 11: Public Defense, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Counties, Cities, and Towns [House], Chapters 34-43 (inclusive): Counties, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Roads and Internal Navigation [Senate and House], Title 17: Corporations, Chapter 51: Internal improvements, Chapter 55: Common carriers, Chapter 56: R.R. Commissioner, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Library [Senate and House], Chapter 18: Duties of Secretary of the Commonwealth, State libraries, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printing [Senate and House], Chapter 19: Public printing, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General laws [Senate and House], Sub-Committee No. 2, Chapter 16: The Executive, Chapter 17: Officers at seat of government, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Finance, Sub-Committee No. 4, Libraries (Sections 533-566), Local option (Sections 581-587), Tax on suits, seals, etc. (Sections 588-601) 1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Finance, Sub-Committee No. 5, Collection of taxes (Sections 602-633), Fines (Sections 712-745), 1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Finance, Sub-Committee No. 3, Assessments on Persons and Property (Sections 448-532), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Finance, Sub-Committee No. 2, Assessment on lands, etc. (Sections 437-447), Delinquent lands (Sections 634-674), Waste lands (Sections 675-680), Erroneous assessments (Sections 567-580), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Courts of Justice, Sub-Committee No. 13 [House], Title 51: Exemption of property, etc, Title 54: Concurrent jurisdiction of justices, Title 56: Fugitives from justice, etc., Title 57: Repeal of statues, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Public Institutions and Education [Senate], Asylums and Prisons [House], Title 55: Penitentiary and reformatories, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Finance and Banks [Senate], Banks, Currency, and Commerce [House], Chapter 48: Banks of discount, etc., Chapter 49: Savings banks, Chapter 50: Illegal currency, Title 19: Board of Public Works, Title 39: Money and interest, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Courts of Justice, Sub-Committee No. 12 [House], Title 52: Crimes and punishment, Title 53: Proceedings in criminal cases, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Title 8, Chapter XIV, Sections 183-193 (inclusive), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chapters 100-102, 133-134, 145, 147-148, 151, 157-158, 164, 171, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Courts of Justice, Sub-Committee No. 6 [Senate], Title 37: Suits for land, etc., Title 38: Rents, Emblements, etc., 1904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General laws [Senate and House], Sub-Committee No. 4, Chapter 52: R.R. telegraph offices, etc., Chapter 53: Insurance companies, Chapter 54: Telegraph and telephone companies, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Public Institutions and Education [Senate], Asylums and Prisons [House], Title 23: Insane and inebriates, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General laws [Senate], Banks, Currency, and Commerce [House], Title 26: Vessels and seamen, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General laws [Senate and House], Sub-Committee No. 6, Title 20: Water course, etc., Title 24: Public health, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Public Institutions and Education [Senate], Schools and Colleges [House], Title 22: Education, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Titles 49 and 50 of the Code of Virginia, Revised and submitted by R.E. Lee and Thomas H. Lion of the Committee of Courts of Justice, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - J.R. Caton, Chapters 135, 153-154, 163, 166-168, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1982-2004 [Acc. 50534]., Extent: 4 cu. ft. (4 boxes). (Box 1-4)
  - Title 4: Alcohol Beverage Control, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Title 24.1: Elections, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - Title 28.1: Tidal Fishery and Habitat, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Title 29: Game, Inland Fisheries, and Animal Laws, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Title 46.1: Motor Vehicle Laws, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Title 53: Corrections, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Title 54: Health Regulatory Boards, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Title 58.1: Tax Criminal Penalty Provisions, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Title 65.1: Workers' Compensation Act, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Title 37.1: Institutions for the Mentally Ill and Mental Health, 2003-2004 (Box 2-3)
  - Title 37.1: Institutions for the Mentally Ill and Mental Health, 2002 (Box 4)
- Series V: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 2007-2009 [Acc. 51825]., Extent: 1 cu. ft. (1 box). (Box 1)
  - Title 6.2: General correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Title 6.2: Work group meetings, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Title 6.2: Code Commission meetings, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Title 6.2: Research on enactments. 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 1, Definitions and General Provisions, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 2, Money and Currency, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 3, Interest & Usury, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 4, Certain lending practices, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 5, Equal credit opportunities, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 6, Deposits & accounts, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 7, Acquisitions of interest in financial institutions, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 8, Banks, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 10, Entities conducting trust business, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 11, Savings institutions, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 12, Savings banks 2008 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 13, Credit unions, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 14, Industrial loan associations, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Title 6.2: CHapter 15, Consumer finance companies, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 16, Mortgage lenders and brokers, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 17, Mortgage loan originators, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 18, Payday lenders, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 19, Money order sellers & money transmitters, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 20, Agencies providing debt management plans, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 22, Safe deposit boxes, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 23, Securitizations transactions, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Title 6.2: Chapter 24, Refund anticipation loans,, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Title 6.1, moved to Title 55, Real estate settlements, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Series VI: Code of Virginia Recodification records, 1998-2007 [Acc. 53906]., Extent: 9 cu. ft. (9 boxes). (Box 1-9)
  - Title 3.1: General correspondence, legislative draft proposals, newspaper articles, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
  - Title 2.2: Revision of Title 2.2 of the Code of Virginia, Comparative table 2.1 and 9, 1998-2001 (Box 2)
  - Title 2.1 and 9: Revisions, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Title 63.1: Revisions, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Title 2.2: Revisions, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Title 63.1: Revisions, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Title 63.1: Revisions, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - Title 3.1: Revisions, 2005-2007 (Box 8)
  - Title 3.1: Revisions, 2005-2007 (Box 9)